In our free future, mistakes do not define a lifetime.
Hashtag, no kids in prison, hashtag Freedom Constellations.
This is like one Billboard in a series for this art project called Freedom Constellations,
which is like a project of the Oregon's like called Performing Statistics.
And they do like artwork. They just like make art and culture stuff with like kids who have been impacted by the like the juvenile justice system.
And are like working towards like stopping it.
And so this was like.
The Philly version of one of their projects where like there's a series of billboards in the city that like artists were commissioned for, but also like a big already exhibit.
And I like helped. I was like one of the curators of like just the billboard part.
So it was like me and maybe like I think nine or ten other artists like made billboards like on the topic of like imagining an abolitionist future like with youth.
But like, yeah, I was one of I was like one curator and then Mark's Janquist was like the other curator, but I also got to do one.
And for my billboard, I worked with youth from this org called like juvenile law center in Philly.
And I worked with them like the way the billboard worked is like as the artist, you get like a package, a packet of like the kids responses to like prompts.
Or like in our few free future, I can see and then they might be like, I see my I see kids playing like I see people barbecuing in our free future.
I can smell and then like everybody responds.
And so like you get a packet that's like a bunch of people from juvenile law center responding to those prompts of like what a free future looks like.
And then also you get a folder that's like pictures of the youth.
This is a photo of like somebody named Alex and I just loved her photo a lot.
And so I picked like all the artists get to pick from the groups that they're working with you get to pick like a short phrase.
And you pick like a photo to work with and turn into like art that's like in your style.
So I picked like in a I picked mistakes do not define a lifetime.
That's like a very slight paraphrase. I think of what the original statement was.
And then I think I added in our free future to the top of it.
And then the drawing is just like a drawing of Alex like that's.
I mean my best impression of like what she looks like, but she herself is like a youth organizer working on these issues.
So yeah, the words are theirs and like the images theirs and then I just added their things.
Like I was like attracted to the idea that.
Yeah, I think my main my main problem is just like I don't like the idea of like kids lives being like thrown away because they make like a mistake or a bunch of mistakes like I really have benefited from ability to like turn my life around at different points.
Definitely was a kid that like I like I don't know. Yeah, I like stolen like gone to detention a lot at one point.
And was like in detention like literally every day like and I've been lucky to turn around in a lot of different ways.
And like I feel like those the opportunity to turn around is something like not afforded to some kids.
So I that idea like stood out to me within the big sheet of things that they had said.
And so I want to make something with that and then like yeah, it was just I think this is just a thing where like it's natural to.
To be future oriented and to me that looks like birds flying and also like paper airplanes like heading somewhere.
Like yeah, so I think that's how I came up with like this image and these words, but the like the initial concepts all a lot of them are like things that like kids from juvenile law center like said and wrote.
Did Alex get to see this.
Yeah, yes, I have a photo of Alex like in front of it. It got printed as a banner to Alex is in a picture like in front of it.
Yeah, Alex was super involved in like the even like the show itself like was giving tours in the exhibition of like all the art that like the show is like these billboards turned into like banner form plus art that performance statistics has made with like young abolitionists over like the last I think 10 years.
And they brought in like some of the youth that we work with to also like give tours and like like work the show like talk to people at the show.
So Alex definitely was one of the people that like was talking to people at the show.